[{
    "theme": "Consumeren (Snel Engels) ðŸŒ±",
    "langread": "en",
    "questions": [
        { "question": "the animal", "answers": ["het dier"] },
        { "question": "animal rights", "answers": ["het dierenrecht"] },
        { "question": "the body", "answers": ["het lichaam"] },
        { "question": "the part", "answers": ["het deel"] },
        { "question": "the slaughterhouse", "answers": ["het slachthuis"] },
        { "question": "the calf", "answers": ["het kalf"] },
        { "question": "the vegan", "answers": ["de veganist"] },
        { "question": "the meat eaters", "answers": ["de vleeseters"] },
        { "question": "the meat substitute", "answers": ["de vleesvervanger"] },
        { "question": "livestock farming", "answers": ["de veeteelt"] },
        { "question": "vegetarianism", "answers": ["het vegetarisme"] },
        { "question": "the climate", "answers": ["het klimaat"] },
        { "question": "the environment", "answers": ["het milieu"] },
        { "question": "global warming", "answers": ["de opwarming"] },
        { "question": "CO2 emission", "answers": ["de CO2-uitstoot"] },
        { "question": "cruel", "answers": ["wreed"] },
        { "question": "sentimental", "answers": ["sentimenteel"] },
        { "question": "polluting", "answers": ["vervuilend"] },
        { "question": "serious", "answers": ["ernstig"] },
        { "question": "animal (adj.)", "answers": ["dierlijk"] },
        { "question": "healthy", "answers": ["gezond"] },
        { "question": "vegetarian (adj.)", "answers": ["vegetarisch"] },
        { "question": "to realize", "answers": ["beseffen"] },
        { "question": "to protect", "answers": ["beschermen"] },
        { "question": "to produce", "answers": ["produceren"] },
        { "question": "to kill", "answers": ["doden"] },
        { "question": "to slaughter", "answers": ["slachten"] },
        { "question": "to refuse", "answers": ["weigeren"] },
        { "question": "to grow up", "answers": ["opgroeien"] },
        { "question": "to emit", "answers": ["uitstoten"] },
        { "question": "to take care of", "answers": ["zorgen voor"] },
        { "question": "to defend oneself", "answers": ["zich verdedigen"] },
        { "question": "to take care of oneself", "answers": ["zich verzorgen"] },
        { "question": "to suffer", "answers": ["lijden"] },
        { "question": "to die", "answers": ["sterven"] },
        { "question": "to replace", "answers": ["vervangen"] },
        { "question": "to eat up", "answers": ["opeten"] },
        { "question": "to have risk of", "answers": ["risico hebben op"] },
        { "question": "to be right", "answers": ["gelijk hebben"] },
        { "question": "in the end", "answers": ["op het einde"] },
        { "question": "before", "answers": ["voordat"] },
        { "question": "when (past)", "answers": ["toen"] },
        { "question": "during", "answers": ["tijdens"] },
        { "question": "after", "answers": ["na"] },
        { "question": "eventually", "answers": ["uiteindelijk"] },
        { "question": "program makers", "answers": ["de programmamakers"] },
        { "question": "the audience", "answers": ["het publiek"] },
        { "question": "oxygen", "answers": ["zuurstof"] },
        { "question": "female deer", "answers": ["de hinde"] },
        { "question": "pigeon", "answers": ["de duif"] },
        { "question": "lobster", "answers": ["de kreeft"] },
        { "question": "ants", "answers": ["de mieren"] },
        { "question": "grasshoppers", "answers": ["de sprinkhanen"] },
        { "question": "caterpillars", "answers": ["de rupsen"] },
        { "question": "snails", "answers": ["de slakken"] },
        { "question": "deforestation", "answers": ["de ontbossing"] },
        { "question": "crueler", "answers": ["wreder"] }
    ]
}]
